Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a health pickup system.
So if my player character is damaged and they lose one of our hearts with our health pickup system,
if my player character collects it, they'll be killed.
So in order to create the system, head over to the items order and just right click on the Apple pickup
and go duplicate.
Put this all health care.
Next head over to the images folder inside of your widget blueprint and just right click on the heart
wall and goes fractions and create a sprite.
Next, if we go back to our items, order, open up the health, pick up and go over to the viewport
and select the paper sprite.
Change this to be the heart sprite.
That way our player will know it's a health pick up.
Now it's quite big, so just get it down so it fits in the capsule collision.
Once you've done that, head over to the then graph and we can just delete all the nodes which reference
our apples.
Then if we just close this and go over to our player character.
We need to create a new variable.
So go over to the variables tab and call this max health.
Undesirable type.
Change this to be a float.
And just go compile.
So the reason we're creating a max health variable is because with our health pick up, if we collect
it, we're not going to give our player character any more health if they're on max health.
If we go to the B.B. King play after we do all of this track in our max health and look for set max
health and then drag in our health and forget health and just connect this to here.
So our max health is going to be whatever our characters health is at the start of the game.
Next, if we just compile and go back to the health pick up, we're only going to give our player character
more health if they're not already on max health.
So in order to do this, we can drag up here and not forget health and connect the notes here.
Then we can drag okay again and not forget max health.
And connect the nodes here.
So if my player character has maxed out, when they pick up a health pick up, we're going to do nothing.
If they don't, then we're going to give our character one more piece of health.
So if we drag in as player VP reference and just drag up here and look for get health.
And to strike a fair and add and undervalue one.
So every time I play a character picks up a heel, pick up will give them one more health.
Then we want to just wrap up here and look for cramp and look for cramp.
Float under minimum value, put one and under max value.
Just drag off here and look for get max health and connect this here.
So we're just clamping this value like we did last time.
That way, our player character can never have more health than max health.
Then we just want to drag off here and look for set health.
And connect with return value into here and hook up false into here.
Okay, So after we give our player character more health, we need to update our heart.
So our heart is reflected that we have more health.
In order to do this, we can just close this and go back to our Widget blueprint and we will open up
the player HUD.
We went ahead of it.
The growth.
And in some free space, just right click and add custom event and pull this show art.
So if you remember when we made our player character get damaged, we get the last heart that they have
and then we remove it and add it to this lost heart array reference, and then we remove it from our
heart reference.
So when we show a heart, we are going to drag in our Lost Heart reference, which has a collection
of all the hearts that we have lost.
And we just want to drag up here and get the length.
And then we just drag up it and look for subtract.
And we want to subtract this from one.
So the reason we're subtracting this by one is because let's say I have lost one heart in my lost heart
reference because arrays start counting from the number zero, it would count it that I have lost two
hearts.
So we just need to subtract one because arrays start counting from the number zero.
After we've done this, we just want to drag in our lost heart reference and look, we'll get lost heart
reference and just drag up here, will get a copy and just hook up the value here.
So this will get a copy of the lost heart that we've lost.
We then want to just drag off here and look for is valid.
What this node will basically do is just check to see that we are actually referencing a heart.
After we do this.
If you remember earlier in our Hot Widget blueprint, we created this custom event called Ad Hoc.
So if I go back to my heart, when we show our heart, we are going to just get the heart that we've
lost and to struggle for it and call the ad part plus event.
And this will make our heart visible again.
Now that we've added our heart again, we're going to add this back to our heart reference, which keeps
a track of all the hearts that we have.
So I'm going to drag in my heart reference and just drag up here and look for ADD.
And then connect this into here.
And it's good to hear.
Then next, we're going to remove this heart from our lost heart reference.
And we've now added our heart again.
So if we drag in our lost heart reference and look for remove.
Item and just double click here.
And pick up this note here.
So now if I close this.
And go to my items and to my health pick up.
We can delete this update, Apple's custom event, and we're going to drag up here and look for the
show hot customer event and just hook up all the nodes here.
Now, if I could compile and save, we can now test this all out.
So if I close this, then if I drag in my heart blueprint and under location, I'm going to put this
in 20 e y axis because all my actors are on that axis.
And now if I go play and I try to pick up my heart, I can't pick it up.
Let's say I get damaged, so I'm going to let that scan to damage me.
At least one of my hearts.
And if I go and pick it up, the heart disappears and then my heart is updated.
So with that, we have created a health pickup.